Badr HAMRAOUY

(709)701-2711 | <u>hamraouy@gmail.com</u> | <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/badr-hamraouy/</u> **Salesforce Portfolio**: <u>https://badrhamraouyportfolio-dev-ed.develop.my.site.com/</u>

Somerset, Toronto, ON K1P 4X0 (willing to relocate)

Eligible to work in Canada

Salesforce Developer & Administrator

Professional Summary

Hardworking Tech-savvy with **1 year** of experience as a **Java Swing Designer & Developer**, **3 years** of experience as an **IT Support Technician in both India and Hungary**, and with almost **2 years** of experience as an **IT Teacher**. Certified **Salesforce platform** <u>developer1</u> **& Administrator**.

Skills

- Apex, Visualforce, LWC
- Java, Python, C++
- Component-based architecture
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- SOQL, SOSL, SQL
- LWR, Site building & layout designing

- Agile software development (Scrum)
- Github, Visual Studio Code
- Object Oriented Programming
- Unified Modeling Language (UML)
- Problem-solving
- API Integration

Salesforce Projects

- <u>BMI Calculator App</u>: Built a web application using LWC to calculate the Body Mass Index (BMI) of users based on their height and weight. Used API integration to retrieve the required data and performed CRUD operations using LWC and Apex.
- <u>Alarm Clock App</u>: Developed an alarm clock web application using LWC that allows users to set alarms and customize their ringtones. Used component-based architecture and parent-child communication to enhance the functionality of the application.
- <u>Currency Converter App</u>: Built a web application using LWC that allows users to convert currencies using real-time exchange rates. Used static resources in CSS and JS to enhance the user interface and perform API integration to retrieve the required data.
- <u>Weather App</u>: Developed a web application using LWC that displays real-time weather information for a selected location. Used lightning record forms and wire service to retrieve and display the data.
- <u>Employee Survey App</u>: Built a survey web application using LWC that allows employers to gather feedback from their employees. Used survey building techniques and performed CRUD operations using LWC and Apex.
- Note-taking App: Developed a note-taking web application using LWC that allows users to create, edit, and delete notes. Used API integration to retrieve and save data and built reusable components to enhance the functionality of the application.
- <u>Personal Portfolio</u>: Built a personal portfolio website using LWC that showcases my skills and projects. Used layout designing techniques and styling hooks to enhance the user interface and built reusable components to showcase my projects.

Badr Hamraouy Page 1 of 3

Professional Experience

IT Teacher Sep 2021 - Feb 2023

Regional Academy of Education and Training

Mohammedia, Morocco

- Introduced Algorithms and Programming Languages to learners based on their levels
- Networking and Operating Systems
- Managed, supervised and evaluated Classrooms (minimum 30 people per class)
- Planned lessons and developed courses

Service Desk Analyst

May 2019 - April 2021

Tata Consultancy Services

Budapest, Hungary

- Assisted users over the telephone, through e-mail/voice mail, and over web interface
- Diagnosed and solved software and hardware problems by giving step-by-step instructions
- Provided advanced support to Customer's PC using remote control tool
- Escalated unsolved calls to the appropriate IT team, Network/Server Support, Application Support team, or other Support teams
- Logged all calls in the Helpdesk tracking database/Service Management tool
- Instructed users on usage of application system
- Learned and implemented new technologies, tools processes, and policies
- Provided training to other staff members as required
- Documented new technical solutions in the knowledge base
- Documented and shared best practices with other colleagues

Technical Support Specialist

Oct 2017 - Oct 2018

Tata Consultancy Services

Kolkata, India

- Analysed and resolved of production issue (tickets) for applications used by customers and clients within SLA
- Daily status meeting with Support teams and business (French)
- Validated tickets logged in ITSM tool
- Acted as a French interpreter for the team to facilitate issue resolution
- Reported to project manager based on key performance indicators
- Tracked on a regular frequency, individual KPIs like average response time, etc.

Java Swing Designer & Developer

Jan 2017 - Jun 2017

Upline Group

Casablanca, Morocco

- Designed and developed the GUI screens for the application using Java Swing
- Used Framework API with customized swing components to maintain the uniform look and feel
- Extensive use of swing components like JTable, JComboBox, JList, JCheckBox, etc
- Developed screen flows and new window layouts.
- Assisted in prototyping efforts and product design.

Badr Hamraouy Page 2 of 3

Java Swing Designer & Developer

Group ALLALI

Jan 2016 - Jun 2016 Mohammedia, Morocco

- Developed new software systems and components.
- Identified and resolved issues proactively.
- Developed client slide components utilizing Java Swing framework.
- Maintained development methodology coding and design standards.

Education

Master of Science: IT methods applied in business management

Jul 2017

International University of Rabat

Rabat, Morocco

Recognized by World Education Services Canada as a Master's degree

Bachelor of Science: IT and Electronics

Jun 2014

Faculty of Sciences and Techniques

Mohammedia, Morocco

Recognized by World Education Services Canada as a Bachelor's degree (four years)

Certifications

Salesforce Platform Developer 1 [CRT-450]

Salesforce Certified Administrator

IBM Data Science Professional Certificate

ORACLE CLOUD INFRUSTRUCTURE (OCI) Foundations 2021 Associate [1Z0-1085-21]

Languages: English: Fluent, French: Fluent, Arabic: Native

Badr Hamraouy Page 3 of 3